# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this video I'm sharing with you
# 酱香头卤
Jiang-flavor Master Stock
# 首先我们来准备吊高汤的原材料
First, let's prepare the ingredients for the stock.
# 其中鸡可以各选择一只老母鸡和黑脚土鸡
For chicken, you can choose one aged hen and one black-footed free-range rooster.
# 然后我们把鸡鸭的脚趾甲剪掉备用
Then let's cut off the toenails of the chickens and ducks for later use.
# 盆中加入适量的猪棒骨和龙骨
Add a generous amount of pork barrel and keel bones.
# 再加入适量的猪皮
Add some of pork rinds
# 原料准备好之后加入适量的清水浸泡40分钟备用
When the ingredients are ready, add some water and soak them for 40 minutes.
# 加水浸泡可以提前去除一定的血水
Soaking those in water will remove some of their blood in advance.
# 同学们所有原料包括猪骨头、母鸡和土鸭子
It is preferably that all the ingredients including pork bones, hens and ducks
# 都最好选用当天宰杀的
are slaughtered on the same day of making the stock.
# 这样卤料的香味和鲜味都是上乘
In this way, the stock will have the best aroma and taste.
# 下一步开始准备香料
Next, let's start preparing the spices.
# 碗中加入八角200克
Add 200g of star anise to the bowl
# 加入桂皮50克
Add 50 grams of cinnamon bark
# 加入去籽的草果30克
Add 30 grams of seeded tsao-ko
# 加入白蔻90克
Add 90 grams of white cardamom
# 加入普通陈皮50克
Add 50g of (dried) mandarin peel
# 加入香叶25克
Add 25g of bay leaves
# 加入香砂仁120克
Add 120 grams of Cardamom Seed
# 加入良姜50克
Add 50 grams of lesser galangal
# 加入白芷50克
Add 50 grams of baizhi
# 加入毛砂仁50克
Add 50 grams of maosharen (毛砂仁)
# 加入三奈30克
Add 30 grams of sand ginger
# 加入甘草50克
Add 50 grams of licorice
# 加入干姜40克
Add 40 grams of dried ginger
# 加入槟榔片30克
Add 30 grams of betel nut slice
# 加入五加皮20克
Add 20 grams of wujiapi (Eleutherococcus gracilistylus)
# 加入黑胡椒40克
Add 40 grams of black pepper
# 加入荜拨20克
Add 20 grams of long pepper
# 然后加入适量的清水浸泡30分钟备用
Then add some water to the spices and soak for 30 minutes.
# 这一步的目的是去除香料中的涩味和杂质
The purpose of this step is to remove astringency and impurities from the spices.
# 条件宽裕的同学也可以换高度白酒浸泡
You can also soak spices in high degree Baijiu (Chinese liquor).
# 再准备干辣椒600克
And 600 grams of dried chili.
# 再加入适量的红花椒
Add some more Sichuan peppercorns.
# 同学们也可以根据不同地区酌情的减少花椒辣椒的用量
You can reduce the amount of Sichuan peppercorn depending on the region
# 最后准备生姜500克拍散备用
Finally, prepare 500 grams of ginger and crush them loose.
# 下一步开始制作
Next, let's start cooking.
# 首先我们准备60升的节能锅一个
First let's prepare a 60 litre energy-saving pot.
# 然后加入所有的鸡鸭棒骨等原料
Then add all the chicken and duck bones and other ingredients.
# 再加入能没过原料的清水
Then add enough amount of water to cover the ingredients.
# 然后开大火将原料焯水并撇去浮沫
Then parboil the ingredients on high heat and skim off the foam.
# 同学们切记焯水的时候必须定时搅拌
Please remember that the mixture must be stirred regularly when parboiling.
# 这一步的目的是防止猪皮压底烧糊
The purpose of this step is to prevent the pork rinds from sticking.
# 有时往往一个不起眼的细节就能够破坏整个流程
Sometimes a small mistake can disrupt the entire process.
# 只有细心的操作才能够保证质量上乘
Only careful operation can guarantee the best quality.
# 焯好水之后将原材料捞出清洗干净
After cooking, remove the raw materials from the water and clean them.
# 然后再次将原料放回锅中
Then put the ingredients back into the pot again
# 下一步开始准备起汤
Next, start preparing the soup.
# 锅中再次加入适量的清水
Add the right amount of water to the pot again
# 清水的量大约为50升
The volume of water is approximately 50 litres.
# 然后加入拍好的老姜
Then add the crushed ginger.
# 水开之后继续撇去多余的浮沫
Once the water is boiling, continue to skim off any excess scum.
# 下一步开始下料
The next step is to add the spices.
# 锅中加入食用盐1000克调底味
Add 1,000 grams of salt to the pot for the base flavor.
# 加入浸泡好的香料和花椒、辣椒
Add the soaked spices and Sichuan peppercorns and chilies
# 再加入高度白酒300克
Then add 300 grams of baijiu
# 然后开小火熬制3个小时
Then simmer on low heat for 3 hours.
# 这一步的目的是熬出鸡鸭棒骨猪皮的鲜香和胶质
The purpose of this step is to boil the chicken, duck and bone to bring out their umami and gelatin.
# 趁熬制的时候我们来准备碎冰糖4000克
While it's simmering, let's prepare 4,000 grams of crushed rock sugar.
# 下一步开始熬糖色
Next, start making a Chinese caramel for coloring
# 同学们由于冰糖比较多所以我们采用水熬
Because there's a lot of sugar, so we're using water to boil it.
# 锅中下入适量的清水之后再下入冰糖熬化
Add some water to the wok and then add the rock sugar and simmer.
# 同学们这一步只需要将冰糖熬成嫩糖色即可
Only need to boil the sugar to an amber color for this step
# 不会熬糖色的同学可以翻往期的糖色教学视频
For those who don't know how to make caramel for coloring, you can refer to the previous videos.
# 糖色熬好之后再加入适量的开水融合备用
After the sugar is ready, add some boiling water to mix.
# 然后我们等待卤水熬制2个小时之后再加入嫩糖色
Then after 2 hours of simmering, let's add the caramel coloring.
# 同学们糖色久熬之后容易发黑
The caramel gets darker after boiling for a long time.
# 所以我们选择了在关火前1个小时加入
That's why we chose to add it an hour before turning off the heat.
# 然后继续熬制1个小时之后关火浸泡12小时
Then continue to simmer for 1 hour and then turn off the heat and steep for 12 hours.
# 浸泡的目的是让卤水的余温继续分解原料的鲜香味
The purpose of steeping is to allow the residual heat of the stock to continue bring out the flavor of the ingredients.
# 12个小时之后再把所有的原料和香料渣捞出不用
After 12 hours, discard all the ingredients including the spices
# 残渣捞干净之后再次开火烧开存放
Strain out all the residue and then bring to a boil then store.
# 同学们初次起卤水的汤都应该打去浮沫防止变质发酸
Remove the foam to prevent it from becoming sour.
# 专业卤味店起卤之后应该不低于3次以上的养卤
A professional master stock should be "enriched" no fewer than 3 times.
# 养卤的意思是多次加入鸡鸭等原料增加卤水的鲜味
"Enrich" as in to add ingredients such as chicken and duck again several times to enhance the taste of the master stock.
# 一锅酱香型头卤就初步制作完成
A pot of master stock is ready.
# 下面开始头卤的简单技术总结
Here's a brief technical summary of the master stock
# 第一
First,
# 初次头卤虽然比较寡淡
A new stock can be slightly bland
# 但其标准是卤汁能够挂白盘
But the standard is that the stock can cling to a white plate.
# 在经过多次养卤的卤汁色深棕红
The stock will become dark brown after several times of enrichment
# 且非常的浓稠
And it's very thick.
# 卤油也呈现金黄色且无杂质
The stock oil is golden yellow and free of impurities.
# 日常存放的时候卤汁与卤油之间不能有血沫
There should be no blood foam between the stock and the stock oil when stored.
# 第二
Second,
# 卤水也分酱香 五香 素菜卤水
Master stock can be divided into Jiang-flavour, five spice flavour, and vegetable stock.
# 此次起卤为酱香
This time the stock is Jiang-flavour.
# 比较适合卤鸡鸭鹅等水禽
Suitable for poultry such as chicken, duck and goose
# 如需要卤制牛肉或者羊肉膻味重的食材
If you need to make beef or lamb with strong flavor.
# 必须打出适量的卤水分开卤制
Must take some of the mater stock out to stock them separately.
# 否则卤水变质之后无法拯救
Otherwise, is really hard to save the stock when it goes bad.
# 造成损失严重
The whole master stock could go wrong.
# 本次的技术总结完毕
The technical summary is complete.